Hello Hello
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте
from the city of Khmelnitsky Ukraine Where are you from
из города Хмельницкий Украина Вы откуда
I'm from St. Petersburg
Я из санкт-петербурга
Russian Federation maybe ingala
Российская Федерация может ингаля
some people say ingria 60 Russia
некоторые говорят ингрия 60 Россия
How do you feel about the war against Ukraine
Как вы относитесь к войне против Украины
Well, to the war, which side I
Ну к войне а с какой стороны я с обеих
don't support the war on both sides Well, you are now a
сторон войну не поддерживаю Ну вы сейчас
citizen of which country
вы гражданин какой страны
I am a citizen of Russia, here you
Я гражданин России тут вы со своей
speak for your part How to support Well, I am not
стороны Говорите Как поддержки Ну я не
supported, including from this side,
поддерживаюсь в том числе с этой стороны
well,
хорошо
but there is no American Ukrainian side
но нет американской украинской стороны
as such in this war No, it is because it
как таковой в этой войне Нет она потому
serves the imperialist interests of the
что служит империалистическим интересом
United States of America correctly and the
Соединенных Штатов Америки правильно и
NATO bloc
блоку НАТО блок
correctly understand that  there is a battle between the
правильно понимаете что идет битва между
Russian Federation, you
Российской Федерации вот вам даже
don’t even need to explain anything,
объяснять ничего не надо
you just understood. For example, I don’t
ты Я поняла просто Вот я например не
agree with you there at the end of this
согласен с тобой там в конце этой
concept. Well, at least not your concept is
концепцию Ну хотя бы не твоя концепция
understandable.  that you stand for the
хорошо А что ты выступаешь ты за
World International, yes,
Интернационал мировое выступаешь да да
yes, you all already know perfectly well my
Вот вы все уже знаете прекрасно мою
position to see through me nothing
позицию насквозь меня видеть ничего
new, I won’t tell you now, you are at
нового я вам сейчас не расскажу ты по
least interesting, you are not drunk,
крайней мере интересный ты не бухой ты
you have some kind of concept with
вот у тебя есть какая-то концепция с
such a person it is interesting to talk
таким человеком интересно поговорить вот
I say yes right away because, for example, if a
Сразу говорю да потому что например если
person just doesn’t have any opinion of his own,
просто человеку не имеет никакого своего
this is empty, you are interesting I may
мнения это пустое ты интересен Я могу
not agree But I’m
быть не согласен Но мне интересно вот
wondering, look How do you feel about Crimea, whose
смотри А как ты относишься к Крыму чей
Crimea should be
Крым должен быть
Proletarian,
Пролетарский
and St. Petersburg
так а санкт-петербург
Well, also a peasant worker to
Ну тоже рабочий крестьянский чтобы
Working Class Well, they ruled it, they adore it
Рабочий Класс Ну им управлял они обожаю
so well, but it’s interesting uh In which
так хорошо а вот интересно э В какой
country now there are examples where the
стране сейчас управляет есть примеры где
middle Working Class is ruled
управляется средний Рабочий Класс
North Korea Cuba Vietnam Laos 400 is ruled by the
КНДР Куба Вьетнам Лаос 400 управляет
working classes or something this is
рабочие классы или чем-то этот
not The Working Class through its
нет Рабочий Класс через свои
representative offices That is, these people are so
представительства То есть это народ так
people Yes People's councils they
Э народ Да Народные советы они там
are called there,
называются
but depending on which post
но смотря на какую на какой пост Нам
he holds several positions for us, he
несколько должностей занимает он там
occupies a military post, a
занимает военную должность
state party Yes, he
государственную партийную Да партийную
holds a party post, that is, he
должность он занимает То есть он
is not directly elected by party members
избирается не членами партии
in accordance with
непосредственно в соответствии с
the principle of democratic centralism,
принципом демократического централизма
that is, lower instances are elected by
то есть нижестоящей инстанции избирают
higher ones  and so on to the very top, I
вышестоящие и так далее до самого верха
just understood correctly, that is, you are in
просто правильно понял то есть вы на
all seriousness Do not say that the people of the
полном серьезе Не говорите что народ
DPRK citizens elect Kim Jong in free
граждане КНДР избирают на свободные
democratic elections
демократических выборах Ким
and
Ким Чен и
he has him Yes, he is
у него
inherited This is an old
Да он по наследству Это старое
proletarian tradition to give the throne by inheritance
Пролетарская традиция по наследству трон
yes And what's the difference in
отдавать да А какая разница по
inheritance  no throne by inheritance
наследству никакого трона по наследству
No, it just so happened that the son
Нет просто так совпало что сын
continues to be done Well,
продолжает делаться Ну что
I can’t understand the huge
я не могу понять огромный
proletarian masses
пролетарские массы
Damn, in short Kim is modern, he
Блин короче Ким это современный он
worked as a worker
работал как рабочий
but he held a party position of the party
но он занимал партийную должность партии
yes, that is, look it turns out He has
да то есть смотри получается Он как
never worked as a Working Class That is
Рабочий Класс не работал никогда То есть
he was essentially already an intelligentsia, but it
он по сути был уже интеллигенция Но это
doesn’t matter who expresses the interests of the working
неважно кто выражает интересы Рабочего
class of Lenin, from whom he came from
класса Ленина из кого происходил
correctly from the nobility. And Engels had
правильно из дворян А у Энгельса была
his own factory from which he made a
своя фабрика с которой он получал
profit, that is, representatives of
прибыль то есть представители
the intelligentsia there and even maybe even the
интеллигенции там и даже может быть даже
petty bourgeoisie, they are essentially if they
мелкий буржуазии они по сути если они
become  point of view on classes point of
становятся точка зрения на классов точка
view of the proletariat They they their
зрения пролетариата Они они их
origin is already social have
происхождение уже социальные не имеют
nothing to do it turns out Kim uh,
никакого отношения получается Ким э-э
this Kim Kim Jong-un Yes, he is now
вот этот Ким Ким Чен Ын Да он сейчас
simply and he himself is not a proletarian, he
просто и сам он не Пролетарий он
fulfills the will of the proletariat Well,
исполняет волю пролетарии Ну Смотрите
look, if we are from the point of view of
смотрите если мы с точки зрения
dialectics  let's go to this, you know what
диалектики пойдём к этому знаете что
dialectics is
такое диалектика
Yes, here's the proletariat, as translated from
Да вот пролетариата как переводится с
Latin, proliz, well, if you literally
латыни пролиз это ну если дословно
say the concept, don't look for it That is, the
говорить понятия это не ищи То есть
have-nots are the Working Class that is
неимущие это Рабочий Класс который
generated by the capitalist mode of
порожден капиталистическим способом
production, people who are deprived of
производства люди которые лишены
property in the DPRK The Working Class is
собственности в КНДР Рабочий Класс он
already in its essence  not
уже по своей по своей сущности не
proletarian, that is, they are already poor, they have
пролетарски то есть они уже неимущие они
already risen to the stage of socialism, that
уже поднялись на ступень социализма то
is, they own factories They own
есть они владеют фабриками Они владеют
factories, that is, there is precisely a
заводами то есть там именно вот
dialectical contradiction in the fact that in the
диалектическое противоречие в том что в
DPRK, like any Socialist country, the
КНДР как любой Социалистической стране
dictatorship of the proletariat remains, but
сохраняется диктатура пролетариата но
at the same time the proletariat itself is no longer the
при этом сам пролетариат уже не
proletariat dialectical transition  that
пролетариат диалектический переход что
he, yes, that he is already poor, he already has a
он да что он уже неимущий он уже имеет
decent standard of living, education did
достойный уровень жизни образование
not want to go to the DPRK to see, I
не Хотели съездить в КНДР посмотреть я
got there as part of a party
был добывал там в составе партийной
delegation with me.
делегации у меня Я же партии
Of course, this is
поддерживает Путина нет конечно это даже
not even a funny joke. And you, like,
это даже не смешная шутка А вы типа
ran for power somewhere, I
баллотировались где-то там во власть я
didn’t run for power,
не баллотировался я
of course I
конечно
did, but that was before, while
были но это было раньше до того как пока
she had even less strong
она имела еще более менее сильную
support to understand when the Union was
поддержку понимать когда Союз Ну
destroyed, that is, such parties stole it
разрушили то есть растащили его такие
how the RP they had
партии как РП они имели достаточно
strong enough support they gathered large
сильно поддержки собирали большие
rallies in the early 90s, but gradually, as a
митинги начали 90-х годов но постепенно
result, here is the reaction I just
вот в результате вот реакции Я просто
don’t understand why everyone is
вот тоже вот я не понимаю почему все вот
communist Yes, who live there in
коммунисты Да которые вот там живут в
Ukraine in Russia Yes, they all understand that
Украине в России Да они все понимают что
in the DPRK  built like this, well, the dictatorship of the
в КНДР построены вот такой ну диктатура
proletariat, that is, everything
пролетариал то есть всё короче нужно
was shorter Yes, but you didn’t have to worry about
было Да но не переживать у вас не было
moving to live in the DPRK, you
желания переехать жить в КНДР
know, but I wouldn’t ask myself this, I would
было Знаете но я бы себе этого я бы себе
n’t ask myself this, you know, I want to be here in
этого не просил понимаете Я хочу здесь в
Russia, including in Ukraine
России и в том числе на Украине
clean clean roads There are clean streets
чистые чистые дороги Там чистые улицы
New houses why do you need to go to Ukraine Here you are in
Новые дома зачем вам в Украину Вот вы в
Russia you live in Russia then I am with you in
России вы жить в России то я с тобой в
Russia why do you want to do this in Ukraine
России почему вам в Украине хочет это
but I would like
сделать но я бы хотел чтобы там тоже
people there to live like the DPRK not only in Russia but
люди жили как КНДР не только в России но
also  in Ukraine, but what don’t you want in Finland for
и на Украине а что не хотите Финляндии
people to live, I want to Well, in general, I
чтобы люди жили хочу чтобы Ну я вообще
want the whole world to be as it
хочу чтобы во всем мире было так как
was in the Soviet Union and as it is now in the DPRK
было в Советском Союзе и как сейчас КНДР
That is, when you are a small Island of
То есть когда ты маленький Островок
Freedom that has been preserved and now
Свобода который сохранился и сейчас
holds the Shield against the whole realistic
держит Щит против всего реалистического
world
мира
heroically  - a truly heroic
героически по-настоящему героический
people who do not beg for material
народ который не клянчат материальную
assistance from their overseas masters do not
помощь тому своих заокеанских хозяев не
ask for these weapons to be massively
просит чтобы ему оружие это массово
supplied to them there, they do not humiliate themselves in front of their
поставляли там не унижается перед своими
sponsors Yes, he just
спонсорами Да он просто своими руками
created a nuclear Shield with his own hands and speaks and told
создал ядерный Щит и говорит и сказал
him to the capitalist world [ __ ]
ему капиталистическому миру Пошел нахер
and created himself literally like this
и создал себя буквально вот такой
isolated Paradise on earth I remember being in
изолированный Рай на земле Я помню был в
Vienna, you know, capitalist, this is Vienna
Вене знаете капиталистическая это Вена
there were a lot of tourists that
там были очень много туристов что меня
struck me most of the tourists are from
поразило большинство туристов это из
the DPRK and when we were here I went with such
КНДР и когда мы были вот я с такими
cheap phones they
дешёвенькими телефонами ходил они
really could afford They
реально могли себе позволить У них у
each had an iPhone
каждого был iPhone
or they  they bought it themselves because they
или они сами покупали потому что они
need it all the cafes were packed with
нужны все кафешки были забиты именно
tourists the Chinese right away so I didn’t tea,
туристами китайцы сразу вот я чай не-не
of course, but
конечно но
the North Koreans were amazed that they
северокорейцам мне поразилось что очень
show us a lot that this is a backward
много нам показывают что это отсталая
country, but for some reason a huge number of
страна но почему-то огромное количество
tourists travel through the vein, they
туристов едут по вене ходят деньгами
scatter money, I was just  I’m amazed, that
разбрасывают я был просто поражен то
is, they are. Here’s my friend, he
есть они Вот и у меня знакомый он
moved to Austria back in 1997 Well, as he
переехал в Австрию еще в 1997 Ну как с
grew up with his parents now Yes, he
родителями сейчас уже вырос Да он там
does business there and he says Andryukha,
бизнесом занимается и он говорит Андрюха
I can’t afford to spend
я не могу себе позволить так так тратить
money like they spend it, here’s how you can
деньги как тратят они вот как вы можете
explain this  the phenomenon that their
объяснить этот феномен что у них
standard of living is so much higher than that of the
настолько уровень жизни выше чем у
Austrians.
австрийцев
But in my opinion, this is obvious because in the
Но по-моему это очевидно потому что в
DPRK there is Socialism, because they have a highly developed
КНДР Социализм потому что высокоразвитый
public consumption fund, they have
фонд общественного потребления у них
high salaries, good education,
высокие зарплаты хорошие образования
people can afford, they live and
люди могут себе позволить они живут и
show when they come to a
показывают когда когда они приезжают
capitalist country. Here they are.
капиталистическую страну Вот они
they show that
показывают что
they show it on purpose, they kind of show
они специально это показывают они как бы
it for them on Well, this is the usual standard of
это для них на Ну это привычный уровень
living is normal Well, yes, that is, they
жизни нормальный Ну да то есть они там
don’t look there, it’s us On the contrary, I don’t think they are
не смотрят это мы Наоборот я думаю не
surprised when they see these homeless people
удивляются когда видят вот этих бомжей
there on the streets, because naturally No, they
там на улицах потому что естественно Нет
see them without work  how well, in general, everything
без работы видят там как ну вообще все
that happens on the streets of the same Lena and
что происходит на улицах той же Лены и
then they come and tell me it’s just that
потом приезжают рассказывают это просто
I can’t I didn’t live in such a country and
я не могу я не жил в такой стране и в
they lived in the Soviet Union I was born later
Советском Союзе они жил я родился позже
but I kindly envy I kindly
но я по-доброму завидую Я по-доброму
envy this country
завидую этой стране
don’t envy  to those who were born in the USSR
не завидуете тем кто родился в СССР
Well, look, be born in the USSR and be a
Ну смотрите родится в СССР и быть
Soviet person mentally. These are
советским человеком ментально Это
completely different things,
совершенно разные вещи
many still mentally remain a Soviet person until now.
многие до сих пор ментально советским
So I will tell you more,
человеком остаются до Так я вам больше
I will tell you more.
скажу я вам больше скажу Советское
generation to generation
она передается из поколения в поколение
That is, I was born in 1998, but I
То есть я вот родился 1998 году но я
learned, as it were, these basics of Soviet
усвоил как бы эти основы советского
education, and this is exactly what
воспитания и это как раз это как раз
prompted me to become a communist, I
подвигало меня стать коммунистом я
realized
осознал
that you have, for example,
что у Вас например там
Putin Sechin Rotenberg, everyone who is shorter is
Путин Сечин ротенберге все кто короче
now robbing Russia, yes They are all
сейчас грабят России да Они же все
grew up on Soviet upbringing, as I
выросли на Советском воспитании Я так
understand it, yes, that is, they don’t, no, it’s on
понимаю да То есть им нет нет как раз на
anti-Soviet upbringing, but I tell you who
антисоветском воспитание же вам говорю
was born in the USSR and a Soviet person
родившийся в СССР и Советский человек -
are different things Yes, it’s just here again
это разные вещи Да это как раз вот опять
We dialectics are returning this just
Мы диалектики возвращаемся это как раз
I don’t think that the KGB was allowed
Я не думаю что в КГБ допустили
anti-Soviet upbringing of a person, let’s say they let him in
антисоветским воспитанием человека
Yes, there were a lot of people, again Kryuchkov Kryuchkov who
опять же Крючков Крючков которые
participated fell apart and forgot
участвовала развалился и забыл вообще
the question about the calendar in general I just don’t quite
вопрос о календаре Я просто не совсем
remember, this is the level of wages there,
помню э вот какой уровень Там заработной
if you don’t tell me to convert to dollars Well,
платы если в доллары перевести не
I don’t remember that either, but I need to
Ну я сейчас так тоже не помню но нужно
open it  how to see the food I understood And you,
открыть как бы еда посмотреть понял А вы
I’m now the dishes, but you don’t remember
я сейчас посуду а вы не помните Вы в
what year you were in the DPRK
каком году были в КНДР
Well, in the fifteenth and seventeenth,
Ну так в пятнадцатом и в семнадцатом
it happens what kind of cars people drive there
бывает на каких машинах там люди ездят в
mostly Well,
основном
how
Ну как
would there be foreign cars Well, how does it make sense for us
бы есть иномарки Ну как смысле для нас
to make brands there  there are Japanese models and
на марки там есть японские модели и
Toyota, there are also Chinese ones Well, that
Тойота там есть и китайские есть Ну то
is Well, different cars
есть Ну разные машины
How do you assess the standard of living in
Как вы оцените уровень жизни реально в
North Korea is actually higher than in Moscow or in St. Petersburg from
КНДР выше чем в Москве или в Питере из
St.
Питера
limited
территория с очень ограниченными
resources And here, of course, you need to understand
ресурсами И тут Конечно надо понимать
that the United States
что и США
influence is also natural, they have, as it were, well,
влияние это естественно у них как бы ну
in general, the level of
в общем-то в целом уровень
economic development is higher because
экономического развития выше потому что
they are in a blockade, they are not
они находятся в блокаде не находятся в
isolated,
изоляции
but they simply rob foreign peoples of
а просто грабят чужие народы
Austria so rich So in this-  then it makes
Австрии такие богатые Так в этом-то и
sense that they are limited
смысл что они ограничены
by creating a socialist economy, they were able to
создав социалистическую экономику смогли
make these resources work so much
настолько их заставить эти ресурсы
that they just survived
работать что достигли вот просто выжили
from these resources, everyone created the
из этих ресурсов все максимально создали
most efficient system as much as possible If only If
максимально эффективной системы Если бы
this system had a little more
Если бы эта система имела чуть больше
territory, if it at least
территории если бы она хотя бы хотя бы
occupied the entire entire  the Korean peninsula,
занимала весь весь корейский полуостров
then it would have already given Japan a head start. I think both
то она бы уже дала фору Японии Я думаю и
there and many European countries,
там и многим европейским странам
but due to the fact that it is precisely because of the fact
но из-за того что вот именно из-за того
that there is very little Earth that there are very few bowels,
что очень мало Земли очень мало недр
so it is still, after all, let's say it is
поэтому она все-таки она все-таки Ну
economically inferior  to many
экономически уступает многим
capitalist countries
капиталистическим странам
To shoot a person listeners more
Расстрелять человека слушатели больше
than the USA in general put in an electric chair
чем США вообще на электрический стул
but no, but as in the USA, like any
но нет но как в США как и любой
capitalist country, it goes like in
капиталистической стране идет как и в
Russia there and in Ukraine there or Latvia
России там и на Украине там или Латвии
there Germany Britain there is
там Германии Британии там идет
falsification and in the DPRK publications by
фальсификация а в КНДР публикации
criminal fabrication of criminal  cases of
уголовным фабрикацию уголовных дел
corruption, you understand, yes If a person is not
коррупция понимаете да Если человек не
pleasing to him, then the United States
угоден то ему США
in a non-partisan association can
в беспартийный объединения можете
say how, for example, justice
сказать как например там правосудие
is organized there How is the institution
организовано Как там института
of the bar, for example, developed in Canada Well,
адвокатуры например в канде развит
how are we, we are
Ну как э-э мы же мы этим я конкретно
not specifically interested in these issues, I’m not, well, I wasn’t
вопросам не интересовался я не ну я не
on  court hearings in the PRC, I know
был на судебных заседаниях в КНР я знаю
no more about them than any person
о них не больше чем любой человек
who has seen them on the Internet, but in general, there
который видел их в интернете но в целом
is a worthy institute of
э там есть там достойные институт
state lawyers there who
государственных адвокатов которые
are provided with qualified protection
предоставляется квалифицированную защиту
only by the state,
только государственное да
yes, but there you just understand what the point is
ну а там просто понимаете в чем смысл
again We are returning capitalism and
вот опять Мы возвращаемся капитализм и
socialism under capitalism
социализма при капитализме
state lawyers due to corruption
государственной адвокатов силу коррупции
they are corrupt they
они продажные они там
work there for the prosecutor's office Well, there, that is,
работают на прокуратуру Ну там то есть
they always act in the interests of the stronger side
они в интересах более сильной стороны
sometimes to the detriment
всегда действует его иногда в ущерб
of their defendant, therefore, it
своему подсудимому поэтому поэтому
is necessary to hire private lawyers
необходимо нанимать частных адвокатов
The DPRK does not have corruption, therefore, there is no need for private
КНДР коррупции нет поэтому в частных
lawyers For example, I live in
адвокатов потребности Например я живу в
North Korea Yes, and I
КНДР Да и мне что это вот против
need to file a lawsuit against some official, yes, that is, it
какого-то чиновника нужно подать в суд
turns out, I will
да то есть получается э его у меня будет
also defend him with a lawyer, an official, yes, it
защищать тоже адвокат чиновник да
only turns out Well,
получается только
that he is an official
Ну и что что он чиновник
is not a strife for an official Well, look, that is, it
чиновнику рознь не Ну смотри То есть
turns out that a lawyer who
получается что адвокат который
is intended  the state Yes, he
предназначается государством Да он и
will protect the state in which the
будет защищать государством в которой
dictatorship of the proletariat will protect
диктатура пролетариата будет защита
any state any state the
любое государство любой государство
dictatorship of a class in the USA the dictatorship of the
диктатура класса в США диктатура
bourgeoisie in the UK the dictatorship of the
буржуазии в Великобритании диктатура
bourgeoisie in China the dictatorship of the bourgeoisie is a
буржуазии в Китае диктатура буржуазии
fine flag
прекрасно флагом
as in your concept, for example, in the USA
как в вашей концепции например в США
the dictatorship of the bourgeoisie so that is, as I
диктатура буржуазии так то есть я так
understand it, what dictates  their conditions to all the
понимаю что диктует свои условия всем
other class yes yes
другим классом да да
I understand correctly that in the United States they are
Я правильно понимаю что в США на выборы
only allowed to vote in elections,
допускают только голосовать
but you know, you raised a very good topic, you were
а знаете вот вы очень хорошее тему
tired, such a quote
подняли устали была такая цитата
rules not the class that votes
властвует не тот класс который голосует
and chooses
и выбирает
the one that rules No, he said he doesn’t
тот который правит Нет он сказал не
consider it, but he rules like that  the bourgeoisie rules there
считает а правит так вот правит там
from how they vote Well, you must admit,
буржуазия от как голосует Ну согласитесь
but in Russia they also vote and choose, let's
но в России тоже голосуют и выбирают
go, so you were in some
давайте так вот вы были в какой-то
country Besides Russia, the DPRK
стране Кроме России КНДР
was in Ukraine And somewhere else in Europe they
на Украине был А еще где-то в Европе
tried to leave for Europe, no, Peter has
пробовали выехать в Европу нет в Европе
never been
не бывал
to Finland in Europe  I crossed the bay once and for all Well,
Питера до Финляндии раз и все переплыл
as I studied at the university then I
залив Ну как в университете учился тогда
didn’t have time then I
времени не было потом
don’t have money, but as you understand it yourself
нет деньги есть но как бы понимаете сами
I work in a bank you are a
Я в банке работаю
communist you work in a private bank
вы коммунист работаете в банке частного
Yes, well, as in a state just
она Да ну как в государственном просто
commercial commercial, it’s just how I
коммерческом коммерческом просто я как
imagined the communists yes that is  in
представлял коммунистов да то есть в
my understanding, the communists are against
моем понимании коммунисты они против
particulars Hear against private
частности Услышь против частной
property Of course Yes, you are against
собственности Разумеется Да вы против
the exploitation of a person by a person, of course
эксплуатации человека человеком конечно
And you now went to work in this chain of
И вы сейчас пошли работать в эту цепочку
exploitation of a person a person, well, an
эксплуатации человека человек ну так
angel with who she worked for
ангельс тем кем работала
I don’t understand why, for example,
Я не понимаю почему вот например
modern communists are not going to
современные коммунисты не собираются в
some  worker artels Yes, for example, to
какие-то рабочие артели Да например в
collective farms Why didn’t you assemble your
колхозы Почему Вот вы не собрали свою
nasty cell and say let’s
противную ячейку и сказать давайте мы
make our farm
сделаем свой ферму
a prototype here the collective farm will show how
прототип вот колхоз покажем насколько
effective our production will be Yes
эффективная будет наше производство Да
we will distribute evenly among
мы будем распределять равномерно между
our party members the members of our collective
нашими членами партии членами нашего
farm and our profit Yes And here we have
колхоза э наш нашу прибыль Да И вот у
we won’t be exploited for some reason.
нас не будет эксплуатации почему-то
Tell us At least one Communist
Расскажите Хоть одна Коммунистическая
Party in history
партия в истории
Look, in the history of the USSR there was already
Смотри вот в истории СССР был аж
collectivization forcibly gathering on a
коллективизация насильно собирание в
collective farm Yes, by force What was violence What was
колхоза Да насильно А в чём насилие А в
violence it was, we just
чём насилие это было мы же только что
found out that this was done by
выяснили что это делалось путём
explaining the advantage of entry  in front of
объяснения преимущество входа перед
individual qualities Yes, there was everything
единоличными качествами Да было и и всё
and people were taken away from them and taken away
и людей забирались куд у них и забирали
Look why are you all the communists of
Вот смотри Почему вы вот все коммунисты
Russia here in your party How many party
России вот в вашей партии Сколько у вас
members do you have in Russia
членов партии по России
members of the party But in general this is classified
членов партии Но вообще-то это секретная
information classified information
информация секретная информация Почему
and don’t really create a collective
вы не соберётесь и не создадите реально
farm, so that’s why if you first need to
колхоз так вот зачем если нужно сначала
destroy the bourgeois system and then
буржуазный строй разрушить а потом как
just you are an example because we are people,
раз Вы пример потому что мы люди смотри
we look at capitalism well under
мы смотрим при капитализме хорошо при
communism
коммунизме
And you would show, look at our
А вы бы показали смотрите вот наша
Communist cell it’s impossible
Коммунистическая ячейка это невозможно
It’s simply impossible It’s like a society
Это просто невозможно Это как общество
now  is in the ownership
сейчас находится во владельческом
as communism advances society
по мере продвижения коммунизма общество
grows And you are now proposing the first You
растёт А вы сейчас предлагаете перво Вы
can learn
можете учить там
differential calculus there
дифференциальное исчисления
you are such a communist It’s not just
пошел ты такой коммунист Это не просто
some know there Brainless kid
какой-то знаешь там Парниша безмозглый
you really understand all these processes
ты реально понимаешь все эти процессы
went to the bank not just even to a factory
пошел в банк не просто даже на завод
somewhere -  then he works for some bourgeois and you
где-то на Буржуа какого-то работает а ты
went to the bank, what difference does it make where you
пошел в банк ты какая разница где
work What difference does it make where
работаешь Какая разница где сейчас
you work now if you don’t just sell your
работаю если ты не просто продаешь свой
work to the bourgeoisie, you help this bourgeois
труд буржу ты помогаешь этому Буржуа
to cash in on your fellow citizens, he also
наживаться на твоих согражданах он же
gives money to them at interest yes
дает под проценты деньги им да
That is, you work  you can work, you can
То есть ты работать можно работать можно
work with anyone you unleashed an imperialist war And you went to work, for example, you make cartridges for them
пошёл работать например патроны для них
Well, take the First World War of
Ну так Возьмите Первую мировую войну
1914, many communists
1914 года многие коммунисты
really were not only cartridges they
действительно были не только патроны
made, they were also at the forefront what
делали они еще и на передовой были что
they did agitated agitated
они делали агитировали агитировали
Just I want to figure it out I just
Просто я хочу разобраться Я просто
I met you for the first time I really liked
впервые встретил очень понравилось
you went to work in a bank
ты пошёл работать в банке
Yes, I Well, as a financial expert,
Да я Ну как финансовый Эксперт
Grandma Proletarian comes to her, she
приходит бабушка Пролетарка ей не
lacks
хватает
Well, well, roughly speaking, but although in
Ну как ну грубо говоря так но хотя на
practice it looks a little different
практике это по-другому немного
in practice, see grandmother
выглядеть на практике смотри бабушку У
She doesn’t have her capitalist system
нее нету её капиталистический строй
brought what to her  you need medicine, she
довел что ей нужно лекарства она
comes and you understand that by taking a loan
приходит и ты понимаешь что взяв кредит
and a loan you will drive her even more into
и кредит ты ее загонишь еще больше в
Kabbalah Yes, because this percentage
каббалу Да потому что вот этот процент
is obtained yes from the loan
получается да с кредита
it will be exploitation That is, you are in this
это будет эксплуатация То есть ты в этой
chain You don’t just understand
цепочке Ты не просто понимаешь
the chains all in one boiler there then  and the thing is
цепочки все все в одном котле там то и
that everything is in one boiler It doesn’t matter who
дело что все в одном котле Не важно кто
works, you can work as a manager, you
Кем работает можно работать менеджером
can once again
можно ещё раз можно самому на себя
work for yourself, take it and go, for example, get out
работать взять и пойти например вылезать
figurines, sell figurines, you can, and
статуэтки продавать статуэтки можно и
so
так
well, you really succeed If, for example,
ну ты реально получается Если я например
you went to work
вы пошел работать
if you understand that the bank is  structure
если ты понимаешь что банк это структура
that
которая
works I'm in this place
работает я на этом месте
if you're a communist You shouldn't
если ты коммунист Ты не должен этого
do
делать
this Why did you get this Come on again you're a
Да чего ты взял такое Давай еще раз ты
communist instead of telling
коммунист вместо того чтобы говорить
people banks Evil you went to work in a ban
людям банки Зло ты пошел работать в бан
and now look banks are not evil banks are not
и теперь смотри банки не зло банки не
evil banks are the ideal form
зло банки это идеальная форма
public accounting, this is still Lenin
общественного счетоводства это еще Ленин
wrote, moreover, he said that there
писал более того он говорил что банки
are no banks Yes, nothing is evil at all, good and evil,
нет Да ничего не зло вообще добро и зло
forget these categories or
забудьте эти категории или рассуждают
people argue Well, obviously not your level is
люди Ну явно не твоего уровня ниже
much lower, so
гораздо так вот банки Это не злобанки
here are the banks.  clarified
капиталистические системы еще он уточнил
that Socialism is not born in the depths of capitalism,
что Социализм он В недрах капитализма не
that is, but there are exceptions, there are
зарождается то есть но есть исключения
exceptions, just banks,
есть исключение как раз банки это
for example, banks as an ideal form of
Например банки как идеальную форму
public accounting and all that
общественного счетоводства и все что
remains to be done, that is, to
остается сделать То есть это
nationalize them to unite a single
национализировать их объединить единый
state bank, which actually
государственный банк что собственно и
was done in the seventeenth year in  the first
было сделано в семнадцатом году в первых
decrees of the Soviet government, that is, the banks
декретах Советской власти то есть банки
merged into one bank,
слились в один банк
accused into one and nationalized,
обвинили в один и национализировали
says that it’s evil that the cannon is evil because
говорит что зло что пушка зло потому что
it shoots at people like that No, this
она стреляет по людям так Нет это
relationship is evil that forces the cannon
отношения зло которое вынуждает пушку
to shoot at people
стрелять по людям
I understand the
Я так понимаю
concept of revolutionary progression yes
концепции революционного прогрессии да
Well, how
Ну как
progressive well  some kind of
прогрессивно ну какое-то понятие такое
loose concept I don’t know revolutionary before
растяжимое не знаю революционного до
revolutionary changes in formation like this I
революционные смены формации вот так
said
сказал
revolutionary Marxism how else how did I
революционного марксизма как еще как я
find your article on VKontakte
нашел ВКонтакте твою статейку
Revolutionary progressivism to Satan
Революционный прогрессизм сатане
our communism you wrote yes
коммунизм наш ты писал да
No it’s another Yegor Shmelev
Нет это другой Егор Шмелев
Yes it’s
Да
interesting just because I became interested in
интересно просто так заинтересовался мне
just the capitalist approach I immediately
просто капиталистический подход я сразу
I think How do you know how do you know my name is the
думаю А как ты откуда ты знаешь как меня
flag of Ukraine behind me
за мной флаг Украины
is the most powerful economy and intelligence agencies of
стоит мощнейшая экономика и спецслужбы
the world United States of America So
мира Соединенные Штаты Америки Так
we have enough
у нас есть достаточно
opportunities you think I just have
возможностей ты думаешь у меня просто
this one
этот
but somehow I somehow recognized it I didn’t care
но мне как-то Мне без разницы узнал
I recognized my look
узнал я свой взгляд
means Look  I communicate with you So
значит Смотри я с тобой общаюсь Так у
I have a good Assistant Assistant looks
меня хорошо Ассистент Ассистент смотрит
here he is there on the duplicate screen he
вот он там на дублирующем экране он
immediately makes a request to I won’t say
сразу делает запрос в не буду говорить
What structure information about
Какую структуру приходит информация о
you comes information about your history comes
тебе приходит информация о твоей истории
about potential characteristics
о потенциальные характеристики есть на
you have and they tell me the ear yes what how and
тебя и мне подсказывают ухо да что как и
for example, they send such things, that is, in
присылают например такие вещи То есть в
principle, according to your characteristics, I’ll say yes
принципе по твои характеристики скажу да
that you’re great, you’re an ideological person writes
что ты молодец ты идейный человек пишет
that in these ties with the authorities unnoticed,
что в этих связях с властью незамеченной
that is, he defends his own Because there are
то есть отстаивает свои Потому что есть
characteristics that people just
приходят характеристики что люди просто
sell there for money there,
там продаются за деньги там в партию
work goes to the party Yes, that’s it  it’s clear that you worked
идут работы Да вот видно что ты работал
in the park on a voluntary basis, and I
в парке на общественных началах А у меня
have a society, of
вот есть общество
course, a
конечно
party salary from the oligarchs.
партийная зарплате от олигархов
Now, one minute, I’ll connect this one, it’s
Сейчас одну минуту я подключу этот
discharged.
разряжается
Well, since we met.
Ну раз уж мы познакомились Может
say the name only Well, tell
могу сказать имя только Ну скажи
Andrew
Эндрю
you are British not
вы британец нет
in Ukraine
в Украине
and I understand my
а я понял
parents moved that my mother is
родители переехали что у меня мама
Ukrainian my father is Irish
украинка отец Ирландец переехали
they moved to the
они в
United States I was born in the
Соединенные Штаты Я родился в
United States
Соединенных Штатах
I was sent to Ukraine to study the
меня отправляли в Украину на изучение
language of my grandparents because you
языка бабушки с дедушкой потому что вы
understand
понимаете что
what  America sends
Для чего Америка присылает сюда вот этих
all these volunteers here to study the language
всех волонтеров изучать язык
good Ukrainian very good
хороший украинский очень хороший Потому
Because every summer my grandmothers brought me from
что каждое лето меня привозили бабушки у
me I won’t say Who my
меня не буду говорить Кем работал мой
father worked Well, I
отец Ну мне
inherited his post, I’m
наследственности достался его пост меня
also waiting for a very good post I need to
ждет тоже очень хороший пост Мне нужно
do my own thing everyone is involved in
делать свои дела каждый занимается в
this  in the world, my work is
этом мире свои работы
like this in principle, but about the DPRK, look.
вот так в принципе но про КНДР смотрите
I, well, what do you think that I was in Austria
Я вот ну вы что думаете что я в Австрии
And that’s exactly what distinguished the North Koreans from the
был И вот именно отличил кндрцев от
DPRK flights from the Chinese, yes, that is, why do we
рейсов КНДР от китайца да то есть мы что
go to Austria, just not to drink coffee,
же ездим в Австрии просто не кофе попить
cities like Vienna Istanbul  for example,
такие города как Вена Стамбул например
they are very good for
они очень хорошие для
intelligence work and
разведывательной работы и
how would he, so to speak, induce
как бы он так сказать склонению к
cooperation, and for example in North
сотрудничеству и например в Северной
Korea Well, I don’t know, maybe they
Корее Ну я не знаю вот вам может одну
showed us one, although these groups of
показывали нам удавалось Хотя эти группы
North Koreans walk in Vienna with the
северокорейцев ходят в Вене с
representatives
представленными
I call them so Pioneer counselors
Я их так называю Пионер вожатыми
walk the streets  by ourselves, but there is a scheme
ходить по улицам самим но есть схема
when a person enters the toilet, he also
когда человек заходит в туалет он же
enters without a counselor Pioneer there,
заходит без Пионер вожатого там
door structures open
структуры дверки открывается
access and Agent former Fugitives from the DPRK
доступ и Агент бывший Беглецы из КНДР
speak fluent language Yes, they
свободно владеть языком Да проводят
communicate and conduct recruitment, I would not
общение и проводят вербовку я бы не
say that it is so rosy in the DPRK How are you Well,
сказал что так радужно в КНДР Как вы Ну
at least  according to that report What I
по крайней мере по тем отчетом Что я
saw not so rosy in the DPRK As you
видел не так радужно в КНДР Как вы
described Because it’s one thing to come
описывали Потому что одно дело приехать
as a delegation, it’s another thing to
в качестве делегации другое дело
come and see What people will say
приехать и увидеть Что люди скажут
well I want to ask about my
хорошо Я хочу спросить по поводу моей
characterization And what else is written there
характеристики А что там еще написано
besides that
кроме того
in full This is all there is
полностью Это все что есть
no good Tell me something about my origin,
нет хорошо Скажите о происхождении моим
something is written not origin no
что-то написано не происхождения нет
by the way here are the parents where he was born
кстати вот родители где родился
Absolutely no Can you say we will add
Абсолютно нет Можете сказать мы дополним
no perhaps I won’t be
нет пожалуй не буду
able to say where my mother is from a
могу сказать откуда мама
little Nevsky district of the Zhytomyr region
чуть Невский район Житомирской области
there are already there archives just there it’s not a
там уже там архивы как раз есть это не
surveillance occupation because  if there are
подзорный оккупации потому что если
archives somewhere in Luhansk, Donetsk region, but they are not available now, well,
архивы но недоступны сейчас хорошо А
tell me, for what purpose do you
скажите а с какой целью моя информация
collect my information, collect my information, or did you
моя информация собирайте или вообще
not collect people specifically about you?
людей конкретно про вас не собирал
you are looking for
информацию Например можно а как вы ищете
technology in the face you determine Well,
технология по лицу определяете Ну есть
they send, I don’t know how they are in that
они отправляют я не знаю как они в том
our conversation is broadcast to my colleague
наш разговор транслируется моему коллеги
Yes, but the meaning is that it determines the police
Да но смысл в том что определяет полицию
Yes, well, probably, I think that I don’t
Да ну наверное наверное я думаю что я не
know they send further somewhere to the
знаю они отправляют дальше куда-то в
service Yes  I think it’s higher when you
службу Да я думаю что выше когда
crossed the border yes you have
пересекали границу да у вас есть
passports in the database these services have access to these databases
паспорта в базе доступ к этим базам есть
Well I do it
у этих служб Ну я занимаюсь
No it doesn’t depend I’m looking for people from Russia
Нет не зависит Я ищу людей из России
who are inclined to recruit and
который склонны к вербовке и
cooperate with the United States of
сотрудничеству соединенными штатами
America
Америки
I don’t fit Absolutely Yes I can imagine right away
я не подхожу Абсолютно Да мне сразу
can’t take a steam bath like he wo
представляешь может не париться типа он
n’t behave like So you see you are
не поведется типа Так что вот видите вас
ours And how to determine for me I’m very
наши А как определить мне Мне очень
interested in how they determined that I won’t be
интересно как определили что я не
fooled look at what points For what points it
поведусь досмотрите по каким По каким
doesn’t detail it doesn’t say that it’s not
не детализирует не говорит что не
inclined to recruit it is written understand
склонен к вербовке написано понимаете
most likely you have already tried
скорее всего с вами уже пробовали
to establish some kind of contact, uh, somewhere
установить какой-то контакт э-э где-то
directly or indirectly and assessed
прямо или не прямо и оценили
the futility of this situation, that is,
бесперспективность этой ситуации то есть
assessed you as an ideological person
оценили вас как идейного человека
Therefore, yes, write your database Tell me
Поэтому да написали вашу базу Скажите
how he personally treats me I agree,
как как его лично относитесь ко мне я
look, first of all, I trust
согласен смотрите я во-первых доверяю
our
нашим
analytical  notes yes, that is,
аналитическим запискам да то есть у меня
it’s not one person who works for me and
это не один человек работает и
double-checks yes, that is, from what I
перепроверяет да то есть из того что я
talked Yes, I see Yes that
поговорил Да я вижу Да что единый
you are ready to fight for the future of the
человек вы готовы бороться за будущее
proletariat there, but the only thing I’ll
там пролетариата но единственно вот я
write down is yes about the bank there was no that you
впишу да про банк не было что вы
work about work  By the way,
работаете про работу вашу кстати не было
this bank daughter was not yours. It’s strange, that is,
Вот этот банковскую дочень Странно то
somewhere profitably flashed.
есть где-то выгодно мелькнули Вы наверно
You probably when.
вы попали на радары Когда вы приехали в
DPRK The fact is that everyone who
КНДР Дело в том что все кто
goes to the DPRK to Syria, some other
едут в КНДР в Сирию еще некоторые
states to Cuba, yes, that is, they
государства на Кубу да то есть они такие
lied like that I was not in the DPRK,
соврал Я не был в КНДР я не ездил
I didn’t go to our delegations.
знаю тогда где то есть вы не ездили а
then to catch on the radar Yes,
где вы смогли тогда на радары поймать Да
understand
понять
in your student years you were already involved in
в студенческий года занимались уже
politics
политикой
Of course, since school now in the eighth
Конечно я и со школы сейчас восьмого
grade you
класса
had a teacher who
были у вас преподаватель который там
talked to you about politics, for example, there
общался с вами политики например
were a lot of teachers, a lot of them just
преподаватели было очень много их очень
talk about politics
рассказывать о политике
No, how is it a teacher who
Нет ну как так преподаватель который
Obsessively not  I started telling
Навязчиво не начинал рассказывать
politicians, that is, I saw you as a
политики то есть видно видел вас
potentially
потенциально
interesting person. There
интересного человека в этом на таких
were a lot of such people
таких очень много было практически
at the embassy.
каждый на посольство
You all will survive now.
вы все сейчас про меня будете выживать
agents yes That is, where
показывают агентуру да То есть откуда
this information was obtained from, I would also be
добыто эта информация вот Мне тоже было
interested yes always That is, you want
бы интересно да всегда То есть вы хотите
to say that among my teachers there
сказать чтобы среди моих преподаватели
was a foreign Agent, I guess I say I
был иностранный Агент я предположение
guess I say I don’t know
говорю я предположение говорю я не знаю
Russian or Russian, namely
российские или российские а именно
Russian, most likely Why look
российские скорее всего Зачем смотрите
where the agents are  but it doesn’t mean that you need to
где агентура это же не значит что нужно
send you black-and-
прислать вам американцы черно-
black Americans Yes, who will be there you
чернокожиева Да который будет там вас
have people who, for certain or
есть люди которые из определённых или
ideological or
идеологических соображений или из
material reasons, cooperate in this way.  I would
материальных так идут на сотрудничество
be
россиянин там статистически не был бы
frank Yes, and I wouldn’t make contact,
откровенен Да и не пошёл бы на контакт
for example, a university teacher with a simple
например преподавателем ВУЗа с простой
worker
там рабочий
there, there are a lot of very different
здесь очень много есть очень разные
taxi drivers there are a lot of there is the same
таксистов очень много есть вот это же
work
работа Под прикрытием есть вот никогда
hotels where
постоянно вот около гостиницы где
deputies stay, for example,
останавливается депутаты например
who arrive or foreigners, yes, that
которые Приезжает или иностранцы да то
is, and there are always 5-7
есть и Там постоянно вот тут там 5-7
taxi drivers right there. They stand almost the
таксистов Именно они стоят чуть ли не
whole day and then
целый день стоят а потом кого-то
visually someone, that is, their task is
визуально то есть ихняя задача им платит
not paid by the client, they are paid by
не клиент на им платят
certain authorities  their task, here he is
определенные органы ихняя задача вот он
driving and the person is talking on the phone, he
едет да человек говорит по телефону он
thinks that he is just a taxi driver who
думает что он просто таксист
is dead and his conversations are being recorded,
подсихи а его записывают разговоры ну
well, something on the phone can blurt out something wrong, well,
что-то по телефону может ляпнуть не то
as if we are flying out there tomorrow,
ну как бы вот мы там завтра вылетаем
for example, there in force or sent there, and
например там в силе или там отправил а
he said here  there is
он сказал вот
already information somewhere This is a very complex
уже где-то информация Это очень сложный
process and so let's just say there are people
процесс и так просто скажем есть люди
who study for this I have a little
которые на это учатся у меня немножко
different yes specialization I understand
другая да специализация Я понимаю просто
I just don't understand why why collect data
я не понимаю зачем зачем собирать данные
on a person waste time resources
на человека тратить время ресурсы
see which is useless we have a principle
смотрите которые бесполезно есть принцип
when I studied  at the academy there was a
у нас когда Я учился в академии был
principle such that you
принцип такой
can always throw out the data, but it’s
выкинуть данные можно всегда а до
not always possible to get to your brothers, that is,
собратьев уже не всегда можно то есть у
you have the opportunity to write
тебя есть возможность записать что-то
down something or take
или сфотографировать Запиши
a picture.
сфотографировать это сможешь Если это не
and here, that is, information does not
так и тут то есть информация лично не
happen personally, it does not take up space on the shelf
бывает она не Занимает место на полке
now it used to be a folder,
сейчас это раньше папки еще нужно было
but now all computer files can
да сейчас все компьютерные можно что
be stored in any volume you like, that
угодно храните в каких угодно объемах То
is, just if you were interested in
есть просто если вы были интересны к
developing a dossier on you, it was more
разработке на вас досье было более
detailed  you would be found by
детально то есть вас бы Нашли бы бабушки
grandparents shorter than whom he met, and
дедушки короче с кем встречался причем
most likely some girl would have been
скорее всего бы Вам бы какую-то девушку
sent to you for acquaintance by chance somewhere
для знакомства подослали случайно где-то
in the library she would have met you
в библиотеке она бы с вами познакомилась
so that is, there would be a lot of
так вот то есть очень было бы много
information but judges from the fact that it is very
информации но судей из того что очень
scarce  your characteristic Yes, well, it’s
скудная вас характеристика Да ну
small, then most likely you were rated
маленькая то скорее всего вас оценили
as a person without a perspective or
как человека без перспективного ни
inclined to a rifle, yes, that is, you see
склонен к винтовке да то есть видите вас
how your ideological stamina
как ваши идеологическую стойкость
was rated Well, it’s nice, it’s nice to
оценили Ну это приятно это приятно на
actually hear,
самом деле услышать
but again Where do you work In which
а ещё раз Где вы работаете В каком
department I
отделении
can’t name
не смогу назвать
well  The service
хорошо Служба
said a lot I can’t be
очень много наговорил я не могу быть
sure that you don’t write down so
уверенным что вы не записываете поэтому
I’m
я
allowed kindness you didn’t say
дозволенное добрости вы не сказали
anything that could
ничего того чтобы могло
compromise Even to
скомпрометировать Даже даже чтобы мне
believe me on my word of honor that I don’t
поверите на Честное слово что не
write down and you will say a lot just so
записываю и будете говорить много просто
that I will tell you when I entered the
чтобы я вам скажу когда я поступил в
training  institution
учебное заведение
in the first year I will not name the
на первом курсе не буду называть
institution you know what our first day was such a
заведение знаете какой у нас был первый
hard day when they [ __ ] us all in Russian
такой нас всех жестко когда по-русски
It was very I will not tell
Это был очень я не буду рассказывать
the details but the lesson was such never
детали но урок был такой никогда никому
trust anyone and since then I will say that is
не верь и с тех пор вот я скажу то есть
honest  I would like to know if
Честное слово это было бы знать
they released it. Honestly, I can’t
выпускали Честное слово я не могу
name the department in which I work
назвать департамент в котором я работаю
because it’s not public. That is, you
потому что он не публичный То есть вы
won’t find it in Google, you understand.
его не найдете в Гугле вы понимаете У
You also have some departments in Russia
вас также в России есть некоторые
that can’t be googled. They are
департаменты которые не гуглится Они
disguised as other structures and
замаскированы под другие структуры так и
some departments do not officially exist in these structures.
некоторые департаменты
It’s clear, but I’ll tell you more, so
Понятно но я вам больше скажу значит
you have a chance to build,
у вас есть шанс построить
say,
скажем
in the Russian Federation, more precisely, in a
в Российской Федерации точнее в
state that will be after
государстве которое будет после
the Russian Federation from what I see here is an
Российской Федерации из того что я вот
analytical note. You saw
вижу аналитический записки Вот вы видели
that you had a Prigogine rebellion, he
что у вас пригожинский бунт был он
showed  the failure of this
показал несостоятельность этой
capitalist system, first of all in the
капиталистической системы прежде всего в
Russian Federation,
Российской Федерации
all over the world, all over the world,
во всем мире во всем мире
state institutions in the Russian
государственный институции в Российской
Federation, you were born that way. Yes,
Федерации настолько вы родились Да что
officials right there, they won’t
чиновники тут же там шо и будет не
think only about their enrichment, and when
думает только о своем обогащении и когда
Prigogine went to Moscow, the whole world saw
Пригожин пошел на Москву весь мир увидел
the collapse of the Russian system  management
коллапс российской системы управления
Generals
Генералы
what will happen Therefore, for those that
что будет Поэтому по тем которые вот у
we have information here Yes,
нас есть информация Да на осень
very interesting processes are being prepared for the fall in the
готовится очень интересные процессы в
Russian Federation, it is in the city of
Российской Федерации именно в городе
Moscow in St. Petersburg that everything will be calm,
Москве в Питере у вас все будет спокой
but that is, there may not
но то есть там можете не постину
be unrest
будут волнения
as a patriot of shooters,
как патриота стрелков
but negatively ordinary pepper  like
но отрицательно обычный перец вот так
this, look at people like shooters
вот смотрите такие люди как стрелков
Look now, remember me and say
Посмотрите вот вспомните меня и скажите
Andrew’s badge You were right what will happen
бляха Эндрю Ты был прав что будет
to the shooter and his imperials and in the
со стрелковым и его имперцами а в
autumn month how the
осенний месяц как
departments friendly to me
дружественные мне департаменты
catalyze
катализируют
the escalation of contradictions between these
наращивание противоречий между вот этими
peppers who, under the power of the
перцами которые при власти
imperial capitalists,
капиталистами имперцами которые
turned out to be no lot  Because the difference
оказались не удел Потому что разница
between Putin and Shoigu and Riflemen there
между там Путиным и Шойгу и стрелковым
is only that Putin, with Shoigu’s money,
только в том что Путин при бабках Шойгу
rides the subway now. Because if
ездит на метро сейчас Потому что если бы
a step came
шагу пришел
to power, it would be the same as with Putin,
к власти было то же самое что с Путиным
yachts there, girls’ palaces, so further, you
яхты там дворцы девочки так дальше
know Andrew, I have such a doubt
знаете Эндрю у меня есть такое сомнение
that it’s not a Special Agent, but you just
что никакой не Спецагент а просто у вас
have a program that recognizes by
есть программа которая распознает по
the face
лицу
I suspect it’s
Я подозреваю
good, super,
хорошо супер
this suits me very much,
это вот это мне очень устраивает
you can even forget our conversation and
даже вот можете забыть наш разговор и
just remember that it was Andrew
просто помните что это был Эндрю у
who had the program
которого была программа
No, I remember the conversation every word Although I
Нет я разговор помню каждое слово Хотя я
don’t  wrote down It’s a pity my memory is good,
не записывал Жалко меня память хорошая
maybe you even remember that the Irishman
может Вас даже то что в Ирландец
remembers everything remembers absolutely very
помнит все помнит абсолютно очень
good
хорошая
surname didn’t say
фамилию не сказал
that we will say goodbye
что будем прощаться
So I didn’t understand And you grew up in the USA
Так я не понял А вы выросли в США
and in which state you want the city no that why it’s
а в каком штате вы хотите город нет что
interesting
интересно
high these mean you have  you
высокой эти значит у вас у вас
Ukrainian accent in any case,
украинский акцент в любом случае каждый
every summer they came to me from my early
каждое лето приезжал меня с маленьких
years, they gave me to my grandmother My mother was from
годов отдавали к бабушке У меня мама из
Ukraine, my father was from Ireland,
Украины отец из Ирландии меня каждое
they brought me to Ukraine every summer and I spent the whole
лето привозили в Украину и я тут целое
summer here I can’t, so I can’t
лето проводил я не могу вот я не могу
speak with a Moscow accent,
говорить с московским акцентом
I understand  I understand Ukrainian
я понимаю украинский понимаю русский
completely I have fluency I
полностью у меня свободное владение Я
write in Ukrainian I write Russian
пишу по украински пишу по-русски
fluently but my accent is the one
свободное владение но акцент у меня тот
I
который среди которого я в основной
spent every summer in my main environment
среде каждое лето проводил
Clearly, you were not recruited at the
Понятно завербовали вас уже в
university I
университете меня
was not recruited
не вербовали
I told you that like Kim Chen  Eun
Я же вам сказал что как Ким Чен Ын по
inherited the post so
наследству получил пост так и
my dad was
папа у меня
Irish I was
Ирландец
n’t recruited, I went there to a
меня не вербовали я пошел туда в
university where not everyone will go,
университет в который не каждый поступит
but you have Ukrainian citizenship, no
но гражданство вас украинская нет
Americans United States of America and
американцы Соединенные Штаты Америки а
American I was born there, it’s
американская Я родился там
clear
понятно
Let’s then it’s very good that there are still
Давайте тогда очень хорошо что есть еще
people who
люди которые
honor their  ideas that are not ready
чтят свои идеи которые не готовы
to be sold and which, in principle, We
продаваться и которые в принципе Мы
believe that people like the communists of
верим что такие люди как коммунисты
Russia, they can become the driving force behind the
России они смогут стать движущей силой
revolution in the Russian Federation,
революции в Российской Федерации
we need to have upheavals already going on, yes, we
нам нужно уже идут пертурбации да нам
empire Yes, the capitalist world could not
империю Да капиталистический мир не смог
curb a huge territory; it
обуздать вот огромную территорию он не
was not ready; there were no such
был готов не было тогда таких
transport communications then, and so
транспортных возможностей связи и так
on now
дальше сейчас
Imagine now a revolution in Moscow for
Представьте сейчас революция в Москве
how many days it takes and to transfer
сколько нужно дней и перекинуть
NATO troops under the guise of
натовские войска под видом миротворцев
UN peacekeepers to all military facilities of the Russian
ООН на все военные объекты Российской
Federation
Федерации
and take under  control throughout the day
и взять под контроль на протяжении дня
I doubt When will it be when will there be a
сомневаюсь Когда будет когда будет
revolution collapse of management everything under the
Революции коллапс управления все под
guise of a peacemaker, see conditional, for
видом миротворца смотрите условный
example, the head of Tatarstan Minnikhanov Yes, he
например глава Татарстана Минниханов Да
declares that Oh, we have treated the paralysis of power here
заявляет что Ой у нас тут паралич власти
and structures, please, he sees a
пролечил и структур пожалуйста он видите
peacemaker, that is, they are just Peacekeepers,
миротворца то есть они просто Миротворцы
as interventionists will come in, there will be some
как интервенты зайдут будут какие-то
for some reason, the heads of the republics give your republics subjectivity;
республикам почему-то дают субъектность
they are in no way in the region. Yes, they are like a
они никак в области Да они как
republic. There
республике
will also be regional ones there, for example, the governor of this region.
это будет не моя сфера ответственности
they have property in the west,
все элиты ваши имеют на западе имущество
children study there, it’s not just like that, that is,
дети учатся там это не просто так Вот то
in the X-hour for the world community,
есть в час Икс для мирового сообщества
they will make a statement so that it
они сделают заявление чтобы это
looks like
выглядело как вот
local authorities with paralysis of the Central
местные власти при параличе Центральной
government asked to protect the
власти попросили защитить
peacekeepers, he Peacekeepers, he will take
миротворцев он Миротворцы он возьмут под
control of civilian military airfields in the
контроль гражданские военные аэродромы в
first place
первую очередь
and  everything will not happen further than this But
и все Дальше этого не произойдет Но
why won't it happen how what will you say
почему не произойдет как что вы скажет
about the nuclear arsenal
насчет ядерного Арсенала
no one will be against whom you will
никто не будет не против кого вы будете
use during a civil
использовать во время гражданского
conflict you will have it all done on the
конфликта у вас это будет все сделано в
firstday
первый день
what is a nuclear arsenal it's not like
Что такое ядерный Арсенал Это не то что
we took pistols  dismantled their
вот мы взяли пистолеты разобрали их
complex system of launching management control, you
сложная система запуска контроля
think that certain structures
думаете что определенная структуры
simply will not be violated,
просто не будут нарушены
but you don’t think that certain people have been working in
а вы не думаете что определенный в
certain structures for a long time
определенных структурах уже давно
who do not
работают определенные люди которые не
shine But they are there with very, very
отсвечивают Но они там при очень и очень
good
хороших
regalia Do you think Gorbachev was
регалиях Как вы думаете Горбачев был
just stupid or that’s all  - did have
просто глупеньким или все-таки имел
connections in the West, of course, had connections, had
связи на западе конечно имел связи имел
connections, that is, in order to destroy the
связи то есть для того чтобы развалить
Soviet Union, a state with a nuclear
Советский Союз государство с ядерным
potential far exceeding the nuclear
потенциалом намного превышающий ядерный
potential of the Russian Federation in
потенциал Российской Федерации
territorial military terms is much
территориально военном плане намного
stronger than the Russian Federation now there
сильнее чем Российская Федерация сейчас
were enough
достаточно было
agents in power Yes And you know this is a
агентуру в Во власти Да И вот это знаете
contradiction  Yeltsin, it doesn’t seem to you that the
противоречие Ельцина вам не кажется что
contradiction between Yeltsin and Gorbachev
противоречие Ельцина и Горбачева это
was such a huge
было настолько огромные
capitalist performance
капиталистический спектакль
staged by the West, I don’t even consider them at all
инсценированные западом я их вообще даже
how to start from the 90th year Yeltsin
чего начать с 90-м году Ельцин
proclaimed the sovereignty of the Russian
провозгласил суверенитет Российской
Federation that there are laws of the Soviet
Федерации что там законы Советского
Union We now do not obey we
Союза Мы теперь не подчиняемся у нас
will have laws  The USSR above
будут законы СССР выше
Gorbachev was recruited, I don’t know who Well, it’s
Горбачёв был завербован не знаю кем Ну
definitely my professional opinion
однозначно моё профессиональное мнение
that he was an agent just like that, the
что он был агентом просто так
cards of the card formed after that, when the
карты карты сложились после этого когда
Soviet Union hands Well, why did the capitalists
Советский Союз рук Ну почему капиталисты
before the Americans help Yeltsin
до американские они помогли ельцину
stay in power, but it was possible to
остаться у власти да ведь можно было
crush the economic Yes, like the DPRK and there
задавить экономические Да как КНДР и там
if you had chaos there, some
бы было у вас хаос там какие-то бы
communists would come again Zyuganov, you
коммунисты снова пришли Зюганов вы
came to power, for example, vegans, he is a
пришел к власти например веганов он
capitalist, he is a servant of the capitalists, the
капиталист он слуга капиталистов
essence is that due to economic problems, the
суть том что из-за экономических проблем
revolutionary situation has matured, the West
Созрела Революционная ситуация Запад не
could not allow this, therefore, there were these legs of
мог это допустить поэтому были эти ножки
Bush, economic assistance to Russia for
Буша экономическая помощь России для
in order for Yeltsin to be his Agent Yes, it
того чтобы Ельцин своим Агенту Да можно
was possible to resist how Putin became this
было устоять как стал Путин этим
ruler Ukrainians think that Putin
правителем украинцы думают что там Путин
attacked them there Yes, look Putin served
на них напал Да смотрите Путин э служил
in Germany the
в Германии
GDR is
ГДР это
Western and Eastern
западных и восточных
somehow
каким-то образом
Putin becomes an
Путин встает
assistant to Sobchak who does not need to
помощником собчака который не надо вам
tell you who he was  yes And for whom
рассказывать кем он был да И на кого
did he work after that once and some
работал после этого его раз и какого-то
just a guy is made prime minister
просто паренька делают премьер-министром
and then they do This is a picture like that
а потом делают Вот это картинку типа что
Yeltsin’s successor then renounced on
преемник да Ельцин тогда отрекся в
New Year’s Eve I put on everything badly And then,
Новогоднюю ночью я там плохо надел все И
until the choice, the acting
вот дальше до выбора исполняет
prime minister  and they vote for him,
обязанности премьер-министр и за него
fake democracy, it was done,
голосуют фейковая демократия сделано
Yeltsin was already getting old, it was clear that Yeltsin would
Ельцин уже старел было ясно что Ельцин
already go out of his mind and
Вот и уже выживет из ума и
America needed to put in a new
Америке нужно было поставить нового
person, but do it in such a way that without
человека но сделать это так чтобы Без
risk, because
риска потому что на выборах мог победить
one of the really opposition
кто-то из действительно оппозиционных
candidates could win the elections, so they did  such
кандидатов поэтому сделали такую
an operation successor Ok, I understand this is the
операцию преемник Хорошо я понял это
last question Do you broadcast it
последний вопрос А вы транслируете это
somewhere or not
где-то или нет
it's just just recording I'm sitting
это просто просто записываете
all day working well maybe
Я целый день Сижу работаю ну может быть
you have it somewhere on YouTube or in social networks
вы его где-то на YouTube или в соцсетях
Yes I understand Well you don't need it like
Да я понял Ну вам это не нужно как бы
dialogue is enough for you,
вам достаточно диалога
what are you good at? There are still a couple of questions,
а что вы хорошо Нет еще пару вопросов
after all. An interesting person,
все-таки Интересный человек
let him think that the roulette switched to
пусть думает что рулетка переключила
drink splendor with us a kilogram right at a time,
пить пышность нами килограмм прям за раз
autumn, and the ass was
осень а попок
more and more important YouTube, driving us
дуже и дуже важила YouTube загоняя нас
through quarries into a shadow ban and even a
через карьерки в теневый бан и дуже
rich look is not shown to people  in
богатого вида не показывается людям в
private, information about
частном на показывается информация про
streams is shown in order to have a little operational
стримы для того чтобы мало оперативный
whistle, prefer it right at a time, but the ass is
свисток предпочтите прям за раз а попок
there in a kilogram about Crim video
там в килограмме о Крим видео
information and we wouldn’t show you with
информация и мы бы вы не с вами
you
покажем вам
I don’t know the
Я не знаю
dude began to doubt I was an agent of
чувак начал сомневаться я Агент
the DPRK he traveled Yes oh damn
КНДР он ездил Да
awesome
офигенно было
Yes, it was written that you are not inclined well What
Да написано что вы не склонен хорошо Что
nicely
приятно
published from her party
издал из ее партии Я знаю эти партию